<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>kanthi.io</title>
    <link href="https://kanthi.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://kanthi.io" />
    <updated>2021-03-23T04:56:25+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kanthi.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Making Computers Personal Again</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/making-computers-personal-again/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/making-computers-personal-again/</id>

        <updated>2021-03-23T04:56:25+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The computer stopped being personal. Most of the apps I use on my computer today is on the browser. The data I create and view just rests somewhere else. It's anything but personal. Even development is moving to the cloud with @replit and @glitch What's&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The computer stopped being personal. Most of the apps I use on my computer today is on the browser. The data I create and view just rests somewhere else. It's anything but personal. Even development is moving to the cloud with @replit and @glitch<br><br>What's the problem? Data silo-isation, lack of insight into your own data, privacy...<br><br>The only way out is for everyone to have a personal computer on the cloud. This computer manages all identity, data and communication with the world. <br><br>Everyone already has a personal @Dropbox or @googledrive i.e storage. But just storage isn't a computer. We need to bring processing and RAM to everyone. <br>This will not only empower individuals to own all their data and bring privacy but also finally free up developers from the whole dev-ops saga. Not kubernetes or even render. This is truly going serverless for the developer. Developers can focus on building experiences/views over data. What are the features that this personal computer need to have? <br><br>Open source<br>Permissive license<br>Shared Database across apps (perhaps using @SolidMit + @GraphQL )<br>Web server<br>Task Runner / Queue<br>Automator like Zapier <br>Cron<br>Functions <br>Who's already working on this? <br>@urbit @SandstormIO @cozycloud https://protos.io @inrupt <br><br><br>@urbit : A completely different universe with it's own stars. https://urbit.org/docs/glossary/star/ Complete with it's own OS, Networking protocol. Seems to have the steepest learning curve for developer adoption. <br><br>@SandstormIO : A project perhaps ahead of it's time.  Crowdfunded on @Indiegogo by the visionary @KentonVarda back in 2014. The project moved to being community run in 2017. They support one click installations of @gitlab @RocketChat. That said it looks like @SandstormIO needs more dev support, adoption and most importantly funds. <br><br>@cozycloud : "Built in France not in California". Featured open source apps, built in-house. A password manager, a Google Drive alternative, A notes app, and an app to manage bank accounts. The platform is open source and can be self hosted. Free for upto 5GB. @cozycloud Could do with more developer adoption. Impressive project all. <br><br>protos.io: Very early stage and seems to be using a docker centric approach for applications. According to them they're in "dire needs of extra development hands".<br><br>Overall both as an end user as well as well as a developer I would love to see some consolidation here. This will help drive more developers and in turn end users. Monopolies aren't all that bad? <br><br>I wonder if @GraphQL centric personal cloud computer can be built. It already has a ton of developer adoption, a foundation driving standard. Porting existing apps should be relatively easy. @HasuraHQ are you listening? <br><br>The space is still quite new. I believe has the potential to change SaaS as we know today and can make data ownership and privacy default and by design. <br><br>Who's positioned to be successful and can get into this space? <br>No-code platforms, cloud companies. So @airtable @Firebase @awscloud @Azure @HasuraHQ @render @heroku <br><br></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Data Commons</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/data-commons/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/data-commons/</id>

        <updated>2021-01-08T02:28:04+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/13/ruben-bagues-_DkmMhzrsYY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Data silos everywhere" />
                    You look up a place or a commute on Google Maps. After a couple hours Google casually informs you that the place has an average review of 4 and that if you agree with that rating. It's right there in the notification. You don't even&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/13/ruben-bagues-_DkmMhzrsYY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Data silos everywhere" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You look up a place or a commute on Google Maps. After a couple hours Google casually informs you that the place has an average review of 4 and that if you agree with that rating. It's right there in the notification. You don't even have to switch to the app. You don't have to think about what rating you want to assign to this place. Yes? No? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All points to Google for making it this seamless. Maybe you agree with the question. The place was indeed worth 4 stars. And just like that Google just got some work done. From you. For free.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course they do offer a very valuable service. This piece of information that you've just shared would be very useful, just how the rating of the place was useful to you before you got there. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">My only concern is that this very valuable data gets locked up. I wish all of this crowdsourced data belonged to the commons. See when I publicly share a review I do want to share this piece of information with the world. Yes, Google may use that information too. But I also want it to be open. To add to the collective knowledge base. And if this information is useful for someone other than Google they should be able to leverage this to perhaps an alternative or a better service. Unfortunately, today many internet platforms gather structured valuable information and lock it in. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">All this while adding it to their terms that you give them and their affiliates a royalty free worldwide license to share this information. I think platforms should mature enough where all crowd sourced information is available under an open license and easily available for download and to be built on top of. Stackoverflow already does this. Wikipedia/Wikidata is a stellar example. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><strong>What’s the way out? <br></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We should build easy to use software that allows people to create knowledge day in and day out. Like Google, FB, Instagram, Twitter already do. Only this time we have a way for people to retain ownership of all this data first. Then allow them to share this with whomsoever they wish to. Just friends or the whole world. Let them decide. That’s what allows standing over the shoulders of giants. That’s what drives innovation. The </span><a href="https://inrupt.com/solid"><span style="font-weight: 400;">solid</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> project from </span><a href="https://inrupt.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">inrupt</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a fine step in this direction. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s reinstate the commons. Shall we? </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Getting started with Customer Support on Telegram</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/getting-started-with-customer-support-on-telegram/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/getting-started-with-customer-support-on-telegram/</id>
            <category term="telegram"/>
            <category term="crm"/>
            <category term="bot"/>

        <updated>2021-01-05T15:09:49+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/12/christian-wiediger-GWkioAj5aB4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Customer support on Telegram" />
                    For any business customer support and addressing queries is absolutely essential. While large businesses have elaborate CRM (Customer Relationship Management) systems, small business owners generally need something much more simple. Today we can already see businesses using WhatsApp extensively to interact and engage with their&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/12/christian-wiediger-GWkioAj5aB4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Customer support on Telegram" />
                <p>For any business customer support and addressing queries is absolutely essential. While large businesses have elaborate CRM (Customer Relationship Management) systems, small business owners generally need something much more simple.</p>
<p>Today we can already see businesses using WhatsApp extensively to interact and engage with their customers with their WhatsApp Business account.</p>
<p>While WhatsApp Business account works great for addressing customer queries there are a few caveats.</p>
<ul>
<li>Restricted API access. (WhatsApp business API is currently available only for medium and large businesses only)</li>
<li>Need to have a separate phone number for your business.</li>
<li>Restrictions on the number of users you can broadcast your message. (Currently 256)</li>
</ul>
<p>To navigate around some of these restrictions businesses can leverage another popular messaging platform Telegram. Let's see how Telegram addresses some of the above concerns.</p>
<ul>
<li>Open API access.</li>
<li>You can create a Bot account for your business without having to have a separate phone number.</li>
<li>No limits on number of contacts or messages. (Has a generous rate limit of 30 messages / second)</li>
</ul>
<h3>How to start engaging your customers on Telegram.</h3>
<h4>Create separate Telegram business identity</h4>
<p>There are two types of accounts on Telegram.</p>
<ul>
<li>User account</li>
<li>Bot account</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want to get a user account you need to have a separate phone number. We recommend creating a Bot account instead. Some advantages for why a Bot account makes more sense for businesses.</p>
<ul>
<li>Independent Business identity, not tied to a phone number.</li>
<li>Easy to integrate self-service features for customers</li>
<li>Easy API for broadcast messages.</li>
<li>Seamlessly move to a full fledged CRM while retaining the same Telegram Business identity.</li>
</ul>
<p>How to create a Telegram Bot?</p>
<p>Yes, there's a bot for that. Please follow the instructions given here. <a href="https://core.telegram.org/bots#3-how-do-i-create-a-bot">https://core.telegram.org/bots#3-how-do-i-create-a-bot</a></p>
<h4>Managing your Bot with Telebooth</h4>
<p>While it's very easy to create a new Telegram Bot identity, managing the same is far from trivial. Generally businesses connect the Telegram Bot token with a CRM such as <a href="http://respond.io">respond.io</a>, freshchat etc to start managing 1-1 conversations reaching out to the Bot.</p>
<p>If you're looking for a simpler self-managed solution you can consider using <a href="https://telebooth.kanthi.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Telebooth</a> to manage your Telegram Bot. It's free and open source software with no restrictions on usage.</p>
<p>Please follow the setup instructions here: <a href="https://telebooth.kanthi.io/docs/index">https://telebooth.kanthi.io/docs/index</a></p>
<h4>Publish your Telegram ID on your website</h4>
<p>Now that you've connected your Telegram account to Telebooth you're ready to start receiving messages. Go ahead and publish your Telegram Bot details on the website. Your id will look something like <code>https://t.me/businessNameBot</code></p>
<h4>Start chatting</h4>
<p>Once you have connected your Telegram Business account to Telebooth you should have a familiar web interface to start chatting with all customers.</p>
<p>If you need any assistance in setting up Telebooth or need a managed service, please write to <a href="mailto:akshay@kanthi.io">akshay@kanthi.io</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Telebooth</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/telebooth/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/telebooth/</id>

        <updated>2021-01-02T15:10:22+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/11/telebooth.png" alt="Telebooth screenshot" />
                    At MountBlue we process a few thousand candidates who have applied to our Software Engineer trainee position. Our process involves 6-7 communication steps Needless to say that all the above communication between the organisation and the candidate is extremely important for both the parties. Currently&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/11/telebooth.png" alt="Telebooth screenshot" />
                <p>At <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://mountblue.io">MountBlue</a> we process a few thousand candidates who have applied to our Software Engineer trainee position. Our process involves 6-7 communication steps</p>
<ul>
<li>Send Candidate acknowledgement email as soon as the candidate applies to the position.</li>
<li>Send invite to home test</li>
<li>Send reminder to home test</li>
<li>Send home test result</li>
<li>Send invite to live interview</li>
<li>Send live interview reminder</li>
<li>Send result of live interview</li>
<li>Send offer letter</li>
<li>Send joining date</li>
</ul>
<p>Needless to say that all the above communication between the organisation and the candidate is extremely important for both the parties. Currently all the above important notifications are sent via email. But emails may get ignored because of the sheer volume and email landing up in <code>Updates</code> / <code>Promotions</code> section of Gmail. Ideally we'd want to send all these important notifications via a messaging platform such as <code>WhatsApp</code> or <code>Telegram</code>.</p>
<p>As far as I know there is no straight forward way to get API access on WhatsApp. There's a way out though. Telegram. In my understanding the quickest way to create a separate identity for your business and send messages programmatically on Telegram is via the Telegram Bot API.</p>
<p>Great. We use Airtable as our ATS. So I wrote an Airtable script to send messages using our Telegram Bot. Problem solved? Except that once the candidate receive the message they would also want to respond back with questions / confirmations. For that a Telegram Web interface would have been really convenient.</p>
<p>Is there a Telegram Web interface that you can connect with your Bot and hold both 1-1 conversations as well as send programmatic messages?</p>
<p>Welcome <a href="https://telebooth.kanthi.io">Telebooth</a>. Telebooth is a simple web interface similar to WhatsApp Web or Telegram web that you can connect with your Telegram Bot and hold both 1-1 messages with all your stakeholders as well as send messages in bulk. It might be particularly relevant for businesses / individuals who still don't want a full fledged CRM and can do with a simple web interface with 1-2 people in the organisation managing all communication.</p>
<p>What's more Telebooth is <a href="https://github.com/aksanoble/telebooth">free and open-source</a>. Self host and use it with no restrictions on the number of messages or users.</p>
<p>Is this relevant to you? Do you have any questions or feedback? Please let me know.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>her majesty</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/her-majesty/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/her-majesty/</id>

        <updated>2020-09-13T14:35:11+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/9/IMG_20200911_163723.jpg" alt="" />
                    back in your arms mother my heart skips a beat as if to take a pause and inhale you fully once and for all as mind races to admire you with its limited vocabulary sssshh... ssshhh i'm silenced by your majesty leaving nothing but an&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/9/IMG_20200911_163723.jpg" alt="" />
                back in your arms<br>mother<br>my heart skips <br>a beat as if<br>to take a pause <br>and inhale you fully<br>once and for all<br>as mind races<br>to admire you <br>with its limited <br>vocabulary<br>sssshh... ssshhh<br>i'm silenced<br>by your majesty<br>leaving nothing<br>but an endless<br>dumbstruck gaze
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>SASSY</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/sassy/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/sassy/</id>
            <category term="SASS"/>

        <updated>2020-05-10T00:14:44+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/6/sexy-2339958_1280.jpg" alt="" />
                    Let's say you want to write. You need ink. I've got ink. May I have a bottle, you ask. Not so simple. See ink is messy. You may get your clothes dirty. What if you decide to play Spill the bottle. I have a better&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/6/sexy-2339958_1280.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Let's say you want to write.</p>
<p>You need ink. I've got ink. <br>May I have a bottle, you ask. </p>
<p>Not so simple. See ink is messy.<br>You may get your clothes dirty. <br>What if you decide to play<br>Spill the bottle. <br><br>I have a better suggestion<br>You come over to my spot. <br>I've got a nice table, a pot full of ink<br>And plenty of paper too. <br><br>You write to your heart's content <br>Write all you want<br>At the end of the day<br>You leave your paper behind. <br><br>Here I keep them safe<br>In a locker<br>You may visit them anytime. <br>Make any changes<br>Read and trash them too<br><br>While I save a copy<br>Lest you change your mind<br>Just remember to always <br>Leave your paper behind. <br><br>What kind of a perversion is that?<br>That my Lady is <br>Software as a Service. <br><br></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>FreeCodeCamp Offline </title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/freecodecamp-offline/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/freecodecamp-offline/</id>

        <updated>2019-10-29T13:38:04+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/4/offline-online.jpeg" alt="Offline Online Abstract" />
                    We're running a program called propel.school which is a 2 week free program to get started with learning how to code. 2 weeks is a very short duration to be able to turn you into a coder but it's a start. Our goal from the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kanthi.io/media/posts/4/offline-online.jpeg" alt="Offline Online Abstract" />
                <p>We're running a program called <a href="https://propel.school" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">propel.school</a> which is a 2 week free program to get started with learning how to code. 2 weeks is a very short duration to be able to turn you into a coder but it's a start. Our goal from the program is to give you a <em>taste </em>for programming and give you exposure on next steps for learning web development and how to start applying for jobs. </p>
<p>One of the main tasks that people do during the 2 weeks is work towards getting their <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Basic Data Stucture and Algorithms Certification on FreeCodeCamp</a>. Recently one of our mentors told me that the FreeCodeCamp website was down. That they were upgrading their curriculum and it would probably take 2 days to be able to bring it back up. Something about that statement was weird. Although I was excited about a new project based curriclum 2 days seemed like an awful long time for the transition.</p>
<p>On closer look I found out <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/freecodecamp-servers-update-october-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">what the heck was going on FreeCodeCamp servers</a>. It was heartening the extraordinary level of commitment when Quincy assures us that FCC will never go down. Even if it means </p>
<blockquote>
<p> I would go get some other job and pay for the servers myself.</p>
<p>- Quincy Larson</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This makes me wonder if FreeCodeCamp has to be a web based service that needs to be accessed from the same central servers. Can FreeCodeCamp be hosted on something like <a href="https://ipfs.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IPFS</a>? While we think on how we can make FreeCodeCamp work offline there is a different interpretation for offline FCC that I am excited about. </p>
<p>A dedicated physical <em>offline </em>space for people to come and work on FreeCodeCamp and learn programming. That's what <a href="https://propel.school" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">propel.school</a> is all about. We're looking to start a dedicated space for this. </p>
<p>More updates soon... </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About me</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/about-me/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/about-me/</id>

        <updated>2019-10-29T11:38:29+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     ... some form of distributed trust system “the killingest of killer apps” for the web - Craig Newmark
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <blockquote>
<pre> ... <a href="https://gigaom.com/2010/03/18/craig-newmark-on-the-webs-next-big-problem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">some form of distributed trust system “the killingest of killer apps” for the web</a> - Craig Newmark</pre>
</blockquote>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>ReStart</title>
        <author>
            <name>Akshay Kanthi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kanthi.io/restart/"/>
        <id>https://kanthi.io/restart/</id>

        <updated>2019-10-13T17:14:04+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Yet another blogging system. Yet another website.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                Yet another blogging system. Yet another website.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
